FANIL ZIGANSHIN

A technical writer with 5+ year experience in information security, virtualization and RDBMS's.

I write, publish and maintain how-to guides, instruction manuals, release notes, participate in mentoring new colleagues and developing business processes in our department.



EXPERIENCE

Prague
Oct 2017 - Present

Senior Technical Writer Veeam Software □

(4000+ employees)

- Write and maintain user guides, release notes for VM and DB backup solutions.
- Lead a project and mentor new colleagues.
- Follow the corporate style guide and participate in peer-review.
- Automate doc generation using batch scripts, Help & Manual API and Python.
- Handle feedback from customers, work with PM and QA teams on product issues.

Kazan Jun 2016 - Oct 2017

Technical Writer

DataSunrise ☑

(200+ employees)

- Write and maintain user guides and command line interface guides for database security tools.
- Write articles for the corporate blog.
- Make proof-of-concept presentations for potential customers.

EDUCATION

Kazan, Russia 2008 - 2013 Master

Kazan National Research Technical University
Automation in Electrical Engineering

Kazan, Russia 2008 - 2012

Bachelor

Kazan National Research Technical University Interpreter in the sphere of professional communication

PROJECTS

Some of documents that I currently support:

- Veeam Plug-ins for Enterprise Applications Guide ☑
- Veeam Backup for Nutanix AHV User Guide
- Veeam PN User Guide 2
- And some sections of the main product guide: Veeam Backup & Replication Guide ☐

CONTACT INFORMATION

Fmail:

fanil.ziganshin@protonmail.com

Phone: +420-773768540

Location: Prague, Berlin

Link: linkedin.com/in/fanil-ziganshin

SKILLS

- DITA, Oxygen, Help & Manual, Microsoft Office
- Ubuntu, SUSE, CentOS
- VMware ESXi, MS Hyper-V, Nutanix AHV, Amazon AWS and MS Azure
- Have deployed and used MySQL, MS SQL Server, SAP HANA, Oracle DB.
- TFS, Git version control.
- HTML, CSS, WordPress
- Basics of SQL
- Python for data analysis, web scraping and for automating operations with databases.

LANGUAGES

English: Proficient Russian: Proficient

Tatar: Native German: B2 Turkish: B2

INTERESTS

Stock market, Infinite Jest, history of Abrahamic religions, Natural Language Processing.